[footsteps running]
[panting]
[pleasant music playing]
[cart wheels screeching]
[Taiki] Every morning, there's one person...
who I'm always dying to see.
[pants]
And that person is...
[gasps]
[grunts]
[Chinatsu] Are you okay?
Yep, just fine.
Sorry. I was practicing my elbow pass.
Let me see.
It's getting all red.
- Probably hurt, huh?
- [gasps softly]
[Taiki stutters] I'm fine, really!
[Chinatsu] But...
Oh, I know.
Take this.
[Taiki] She has a candy bar in her pocket.
[Chinatsu] And in return... [chuckles]
forgive me.
[exclaims]
[Taiki] Of course I forgive you!
EIMEI PRIVATE HIGH SCHOOL
[Taiki] I go to Eimei, a private school
that's junior through senior high.
It's got a powerhouse sports program.
Since I graduated from junior high,
I'm now practicing
with the high school badminton club.
There's optional open practice
every morning,
and I try to get there
earlier than anyone else.
But she always beats me.
Chinatsu Kano.
Even before the gym
has warmed up for the day,
she's there, shooting shot after shot.
That's how Chinatsu is.
That's why I like her.
[music fades]
[opening theme song playing]
BLUE BOX
EPISODE 1
CHINATSU SENPAI
- [indistinct chatter]
- [whistle bowls]
[chatter continues]
[whistle bowls]
[groans]
I wanna marry her so bad.
- [Kyo] Not gonna happen.
- [exclaims] Come on, bro!
What, a wedding out of the blue?
[Taiki] Just think. I could see her face...
- Mornin'!
- [Taiki] ...first thing every morning.
- It'd be awesome.
- You want coffee?
You couldn't even date her,
she's out of your league.
[exclaims]
[Kyo] Not only is she
the basketball team's future MVP,
she has talent, she's charismatic,
she's got the it factor.
TO THE HOOP WITH AGGRESSION!
And she's popular
inside and outside of school.
Then there's you, Taiki.
It may be that you're fine, at badminton,
- but you aren't exactly popular.
- [exclaims]
You're a bottom-rung player
who's being allowed to practice
with the high schoolers.
[groans]
[Kyo] Like, if Chinatsu
was a ranked school,
she'd be one of the top seeds.
And your school
would lose in the first round.
You're just on different levels.
All you've got in common
is morning practice.
We have other things in common!
You know, like my mom.
She used to play basketball
for our school.
A lot of legacy kids at private schools...
[Taiki] I understand
where you're coming from, Kyo,
but you also can't win unless you try!
And you know what?
It's fun going up against the top schools.
Well, okay, then. See if you can
make it to the second round.
You know, introduce yourself,
or ask for her number.
All right.
- What are you talking about?
- [grunts] What're you doing?
I was just coming to say hi!
[Taiki] What are you, a grade-schooler?
I wish I was a kid, but as of spring,
I'll be in high school, same as you!
I'll have you know,
I've grown a whole seven centimeters
since we were in grade school.
[Taiki] And yet you're still shorter
than the badminton net.
Shut up!
Oh, you're one to talk,
you're not that tall either!
[grunting] I'm still growing! Okay?
[Kyo] Both of them are children.
[Hina] Anyway, something bothering you?
Oh, no, don't worry about it.
But, uh, just for the fun of it...
What sort of things...
can a guy do to attract a girl?
Oh, is this a matter of love?
I'm a one-stop-shop
for all that kinda stuff!
For starters,
don't act like such a weenie.
You need to show them
that you're cool, calm,
collected, and reliable!
And then, the most important of all is...
LIKE MARCE NGUYEN
...the body of a Greek god.
[exclaiming]
EIMEI PRIVATE HIGH SCHOOL
[creaking]
[Taiki] Asking for Hina's help
was a mistake.
Her taste is too particular.
Huh?
[serene music playing]
I guess they haven't unlocked
the gym doors yet.
Okay. Now's my chance.
I gotta talk to her!
[heart beating]
I'll introduce myself.
Er, that might be weird, out of nowhere.
THIS AIN'T NO JOB INTERVIEW
Maybe thank her for the candy bar?
Then again, I haven't eaten it yet.
I OFFER MY THANKS
Oh, I got it!
I'll ask her what she's reading.
RUNNING A STACK PLAY
[exclaims softly]
I'll just keep quiet I guess.
- [Chinatsu sneezes]
- [gasps]
Uh, um... If you'd like,
you can wear my scarf!
It's fresh from the laundry!
And then... I have hot tea.
This thermos is really good
at keeping things warm!
And also, I have gloves and a hand warmer!
It heats when you shake it!
I've done it now.
I word vomited!
- [chuckles softly]
- [Taiki exclaims]
Wha... what is it?
Nothing, I'm just wondering what
you're going to offer me next, that's all.
[grunts nervously]
[amusing music playing]
[giggles] I was just kidding.
Thanks for watching out for me.
Uh... Sure!
She laughed! [sneezes]
You don't have to worry about me.
You keep yourself warm.
[Taiki] This feels like...
when a wife...
ties her newlywed husband's tie.
- Sorry.
- It's fine.
I've always thought...
Chinatsu would have
a low body temperature.
All done.
- Sorry, I'm running behind this morning!
- [Chinatsu] No worries.
Don't catch a cold, okay?
Taiki Inomata.
[gasps] How do you know my name?
Well, how do you think?
[gasps]
[Taiki] Hang on.
Has she always known my name?
You have a good mom.
[Taiki] Good mom? [exclaims]
TAIKI INOMATA
So embarrassing!
Well, at least she said my name.
[whimpers]
Nope, it's still embarrassing!
[players grunting]
[grunts]
- Good effort dude!
- Nice serve!
Take a break!
[boy] Phew! Taiki.
Could you go wet the rags?
[Taiki] Yes!
[water running]
[Taiki] The good thing is
she knows my name now.
[Chinatsu] Taiki Inomata.
[Taiki] Hearing her say it hit me
a lot harder than I expected it to.
[laughs]
[clears throat]
Anyway, I've made it
past the second round.
Now it's time for round number three.
I'm going to ask for her number!
[Taiki] The coach of the girls'
basketball team and Chinatsu?
- Whatcha looking at?
- [yelps] Hina!
- I wasn't looking at anything.
- [Hina gasps]
- Hm.
- [Taiki grunts nervously]
Don't shoot too high, Taiki.
[Taiki] Like you're the expert.
It's not that.
She just looked really serious.
That's all.
[Hina sighs]
You know the other day, I saw her walking
with another guy, just the two of them.
[gasps]
[giggles]
JK!
[humming]
[Taiki] What a jerk!
[footsteps approaching]
[Taiki] Mm.
[inaudible]
- [boy 1] Ah, I'm tired.
- [boy 2] Nice hustle!
- See you tomorrow.
- Yeah, see ya!
I'm heading out!
Have a good night, y'all!
[all] Have a good night!
Oh.
[Taiki] I forgot my towel in the gym.
What, did you forget something?
- Yeah, go on--
- I'll head out.
[Taiki sighs]
[Taiki] Oh, good. It's still open.
- [ball dribbling]
- [gasps softly]
[uplifting music playing]
[Taiki] I can't believe it.
She's... still at it.
[Chinatsu] Taiki Inomata.
[Taiki exclaims] She remembered my name!
You're still here practicing?
[Chinatsu] I wasn't happy
with how I played during practice today.
[Taiki] There is such a thing
as overdoing it.
That may be true but...
right now, I wanna get
as much time on the court as I can.
[Taiki] She really does love basketball.
[exclaims] She caught me staring.
Let's play one-on-one!
Okay?
[Taiki grunting]
[Taiki grunts]
[breathing heavily]
Why don't we take a little break.
I'm so... [coughs] sorry.
I'm pathetic.
[Chinatsu] No denying
you're a badminton player.
You move well on the court.
My mom used to be on the basketball team,
so I would play with her
when I was growing up.
Wow, same!
My mom was on the basketball team.
Before I joined the youth team,
the two of us would play together.
[Taiki] We have something in common.
It's fate!
Did you ever think
about playing basketball?
[yelling]
Pass it!
I think that team sports
are maybe not my thing.
Gotcha.
Besides, I like badminton.
How it's just me out on the court,
and I'm in control of the match's outcome.
Whether I win or lose,
I can only thank or blame myself.
I enjoy that kind of pressure.
- You're a masochist.
- [exclaims]
[chuckles softly]
But I get it now.
That's why you're always
practicing so hard.
[ball dribbling]
Well, coming from you...
I meant it as a compliment.
Well, I mean...
you were here practicing
the day after you graduated
from your junior high club.
[Chinatsu exclaims]
Must've been a year and a half ago.
I didn't have practice that day...
but I had some equipment
I needed to return...
and I live close by...
- so I came anyway.
- [ball dribbling]
When I got there...
[mellow music playing]
I heard later that your team
had narrowly missed the cut for nationals.
That must've been frustrating for you.
Seeing that you worked so hard,
and only to end up disappointed.
It made me want to work that hard, too.
Come to think of it,
that was probably what made me
like her in the first place.
[gasps]
I'd forgotten that.
Okay! The two of you
should be heading home now!
Okay!
Let's clean up first.
[Taiki] That's weird.
For a second, I thought she was crying.
Thanks for your help.
[gasps softly]
Oh, sure.
Maybe it's 'cause we were just playing...
but her hand...
felt warmer than last time.
[birds chirping]
It'll mostly be sunny
throughout the country today.
- Mornin'.
- Good morning.
- Lunch is on the table.
- Yeah, thanks, Mom.
You're not wearing your sweatshirt?
Nah, it's warm today.
But I went out of my way to wash it.
Sorry, sorry. [exclaims]
GOING STRAIGHT FOR THE NET!
CHINATSU KANO
Chinatsu!
Oh, you know her?
What? Uh, no, I don't.
Actually, Chinatsu's mom and I
were on the same team,
and played basketball together
back in the day.
- What?!
- Why the yelling all of a sudden?
No reason.
We have so much in common!
[Taiki's mom] We've been in touch
on and off over the years,
but I wouldn't have expected Chinatsu
to become such an impressive young person!
It's too bad, though.
I heard they're moving overseas for work.
Word on the street is
they're going to move in mid-March.
It's such a bummer.
[emotional music playing]
[Taiki] Now that she mentions it...
[grunts]
Taiki?
[Taiki] Moving? Overseas?
What? This can't be happening.
[panting]
[grunts]
She can't possibly be okay with that!
She's the first one there every day.
She practices more than anyone.
Even when... she was at her lowest!
All her passion...
the effort that she's put in...
her goals, her dreams, everything!
Can she really leave all that behind?
[door opens]
[Taiki panting]
Taiki.
Are you okay?
Please, Chinatsu,
you have to go to nationals.
You... you're the one who taught me that...
you need to work toward
your goal every day.
And that even if you lose,
you keep moving forward.
- So... please don't give up.
- [music intensifies]
It's not your fault
that your parents are
getting transferred overseas for work.
- That is just--
- Sorry.
I'm not going overseas.
[music stops]
Huh?
Um... Uh... Wait...
To be specific,
my family is going overseas,
but I'm going to stay here.
A family friend
is letting me live with them.
[Taiki] Which means... I...
word vomited again!
Oh, then that's cool!
- [Chinatsu] I was pretty conflicted.
- [exclaims]
I know it'll be sad
being away from my family.
But...
I was reminded...
of the time when I graduated
from my junior high team.
I still want to go to nationals.
I don't want to give up on that dream.
And it's all because of you.
Thank you, Taiki Inomata!
I didn't... do anything.
You up for more one-on-one?
[pleasant guitar music playing]
[Taiki] Why don't we
play badminton this time?
[Chinatsu] Sure thing!
[birds chirping]
SUNDAY
[Taiki] Wait.
I embarrassed myself
the other day, didn't I?
[grunts in frustration]
I'm so glad that today is Sunday.
This may actually be the first time...
that I don't wanna see...
[birds chirping]
Morning.
[gasps]
[Taiki] Why... why is Chinatsu in my house?
Good morning, Taiki. I see you're up.
Ah!
I mentioned her before.
This is Chinatsu Kano.
Starting in the spring,
she'll be living with us.
Thank you for letting Chinatsu
stay with you. It means a lot.
- Yes, thank you.
- Once teammates, always teammates!
[gasps]
[Taiki's and Chinatsu's moms]
We are Eimei!
[Taiki] Is this for real?!
[closing theme song playing]